Guide to the Washington Office on Africa Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Resource/Correspondence Files By Name of Organization, Series VI
  - U.S. university African Studies departments (various), 1980-1984 (Box 39, Folder 172)
  - War Resisters League, 1974 (Box 39, Folder 173)
  - Washington Interreligious Staff Council, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 173a)
  - Washington Office on Latin America, 1980-1983 (Box 39, Folder 173b)
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, 1973-1983 (Box 39, Folder 174)
  - Working Committee Against FBI/CIA Executive Order, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 175)
  - World Council of Churches, Programme to Combat Racism, incl. Harare Declaration (1985);; incl. "The Churches' Search for Justice and Peace in Southern Africa"- report on Lusaka meeting 4-8 May 1987, 1970-1987 (Box 39, Folder 176)
  - World Peace Foundation, 1980 (Box 39, Folder 176a)
  - World Policy Institute, 1988-1989 (Box 39, Folder 177)
  - Young Women's Christian Association, National Board, 1976, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 178)
- Resource/ Correspondence Files - By State or Region, Series VII
  - Alabama (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Alaska (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Arkansas (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Arizona (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - California (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - California - Bay Area (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - California - San Francisco (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - California - L.A. (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Colorado (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Connecticut (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Delaware (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - District of Columbia (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Florida (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Georgia (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Hawaii (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Illinois (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Indiana (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Iowa (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - Kansas (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - Kentucky (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - Louisiana (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - Maine (Box 41, Folder 22)
  - Maryland (Box 41, Folder 23)
  - Massachusetts (Box 41, Folder 24)
  - Michigan (Box 41, Folder 25)
  - Minnesota (Box 41, Folder 26)
  - Mississippi (Box 41, Folder 27)
  - Missouri (Box 42, Folder 28)
  - Montana (Box 42, Folder 29)
  - Nebraska (Box 42, Folder 30)
  - New England (Box 42, Folder 31)
  - New Hampshire (Box 42, Folder 32)
  - New Jersey (Box 42, Folder 33)
  - New Mexico (Box 42, Folder 34)
  - New York (Box 42, Folder 35)
  - North Carolina (Box 42, Folder 36)
  - North Dakota (Box 42, Folder 37)
  - Ohio (Box 42, Folder 38)
  - Oklahoma (Box 42, Folder 39)
  - Oregon (Box 43, Folder 40)
  - Pacific Northwest (Box 43, Folder 41)
  - Pennsylvania (Box 43, Folder 42)
  - Rhode Island (Box 43, Folder 43)
  - South Carolina (Box 43, Folder 44)
  - Tennessee (Box 43, Folder 45)
  - Texas (Box 43, Folder 46)
  - Utah (Box 43, Folder 47)
  - Vermont (Box 43, Folder 48)
  - Virginia (Box 43, Folder 49)
  - Washington (Box 43, Folder 50)
  - West Virginia (Box 43, Folder 51)
  - Wisconsin (Box 43, Folder 52)
- Resource File - By Topic, Series VIII
  - Country files
    - Angola
      - Portuguese export of herbicides to Angola, 1972 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - U.S. intervention in Angola; Gulf boycott, 1975 (Box 44, Folder 2)
      - American air companies involved in Angola, 1975 (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - General articles and statements, 1975-1976 (Box 44, Folder 4)
      - Church-related articles and statements, 1975-1976 (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - Chronology of events in Angola Civil War 1957-1976; fact sheets (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - Seminar on Angola - Havana, Cuba, 1976 (Box 44, Folder 7)
      - Angola Support Conference - Chicago, 1976 (Box 44, Folder 8)
      - Articles and statements, incl. re. visit of Jonas Savimbi, chief of UNITA, 1980-1981 (Box 44, Folder 9)
      - Articles, statements, correspondence WOA/ State Dept., 1982-1983 (Box 44, Folder 10)
      - Articles, statements, incl. re. Export-Import Bank Act, political imprisonment, Clark Amendment; statement of Angola churches, 1984-1985 (Box 44, Folder 11)
      - Articles, statements, incl. re. UNITA, 1986-1987 (Box 44, Folder 12)
      - Chronology of political developments 1961-1988;statements; articles, incl. by Ecumenical Documentation and Information Centre for Eastern and Southern Africa; visit of Savimbi, 1988-1989 (Box 44, Folder 13)
      - Notes of Angola Working Group; articles, statements, 1990 (Box 44, Folder 14)
      - Articles, statements, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - Botswana
      - South African raid on Gaborone, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - Latin America
      - Articles, statements, 1976-1982 (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Lesotho
      - Articles, statements, correspondence, 1969-1985 (Box 45, Folder 18-20)
    - Middle East
      - Re. South Africa and Arab countries, 1975 (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - Mozambique
      - Pamphlets re. role of Mozambican women, 1972,1979, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 22)
      - Articles, statements, correspondence re. education, enonomy, 1977-1980 (Box 45, Folder 23)
      - Articles, statements re. economy, death of journalist Ruth First, 1981-1982 (Box 45, Folder 24)
      - Articles, statements, incl. re. death of Samora Machel, 1983-1986 (Box 45, Folder 25)
      - Articles, statements, incl. re. Nkomati Accord, 1984-1985 (Box 45, Folder 26)
      - Articles, statements, incl. re. famine, 1986-1988, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 27)
      - Photos, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 28)
    - Namibia
      - Correspondence, memos, notes, 1972-1978 (Box 45, Folder 29)
      - Correspondence, memos, notes (See also Series IV), 1980-1981 (Box 45, Folder 30)
      - Notes, memos, articles re. political repression, 1982-1985 (Box 45, Folder 31)
      - Articles, statements, incl. re. UN Security Council meeting April 1987, 1986-1987 (Box 45, Folder 32)
      - Articles, memos, incl. re. political detainees, American Committee on Africa reprint; SWAPO press releases, 1988-1990, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 33)
      - SWAPO material, 1989-1990 (Box 46, Folder 33a, 34)
    - Portugal
      - Re. U.S. foreign aid to Portugal, Azores Agreement, 1971-1974 (Box 46, Folder 35-36)
    - Rhodesia - see Zimbabwe
    - South Africa
      - Economy
        - Industry (Box 46, Folder 37)
        - Investment in North America (Box 46, Folder 38)
        - General (Box 46, Folder 39)
        - Mining (Box 46, Folder 40)
        - Oil (Box 46, Folder 41)
        - Transportation (Box 46, Folder 42)
        - Union workers (Box 46, Folder 43)
      - Political events/ issues
        - 10th anniversary of Sharpeville massacre, 1970 (Box 46, Folder 44)
        - South Africa - Israel connection, 1976-1984 (Box 46, Folder 44a, 44b)
        - Proposal of John Rees: "Alternatives for South Africa", 1978 (Box 46, Folder 45)
        - Incl. re. Young Christian Workers of South Africa, 1978-1980 (Box 46, Folder 46)
        - Constitution of Republic of South Africa, 1983 (Box 46, Folder 47)
        - United Democratic Front, 1984 (Box 46, Folder 48)
        - United Democratic Front, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 49)
        - United Democratic Front, 1986-1987 (Box 47, Folder 50)
        - misc.; incl. re. Azania, 1985-1988 (Box 47, Folder 51)
      - Prisoners / detainees
        - Re. convict labor, 1972 (Box 47, Folder 52)
        - Behavior modification program, 1975 (Box 47, Folder 53)
        - misc., incl Venda detentions, 1982-1983 (Box 47, Folder 54)
        - Campaigns to free ANC prisoners, 1982-1983 (Box 47, Folder 55)
        - misc., 1985-1989 (Box 47, Folder 56)
      - Religion
        - Catholic Church / Southern African Catholic Bishops Conference, 1973-1991 (Box 47, Folder 57-59)
        - Dutch Reformed Church in S.A. (see Series VI)
        - Institute of Contextual Theology, 1987 (Box 47, Folder 60)
        - Presbyterian Church of South Africa, 1974-1984 (Box 47, Folder 61)
        - South Africa Council of Churches, 1968-1983 (Box 47, Folder 62-64)
        - South Africa Council of Churches incl. re. Eloff Commission, 1983-1984 (Box 47, Folder 65)
        - South Africa Council of Churches (see also: Frank Chikane), 1985-1991 (Box 47, Folder 66)
        - General - articles, clippings, statements re. religion, 1977, 1982-1985 (Box 47, Folder 67-68)
        - General (see also under "Southern Africa in General", below), 1986-1988 (Box 48, Folder 69)
        - General, incl. report: "U.S. Church-Related Funding for Change in South Africa", 1987-1989 (Box 48, Folder 70, 70a)
        - United Congregational Church of Southern Africa, 1976-1986 (Box 48, Folder 71)
        - Black Theology, 1971-1987 (Box 48, Folder 72)
      - Relocations / Refugees
        - Bantustans, 1975-1984 (Box 48, Folder 73)
        - "Ruling with the Whip: a report on the violation of human rights in the Ciskei" by Nicholas Haysom, 1983 (Box 66, Folder 6)
        - Refugees, 1977-1978 (Box 48, Folder 74)
        - Social removals, 1984-1985 (Box 48, Folder 75)
      - Social health
        - Mental and physical health under apartheid, 1974-1988 (Box 49, Folder 76-78)
    - Swaziland
      - misc., 1972-1984 (Box 49, Folder 79)
    - Tanzania
      - misc., 1980-1984 (Box 49, Folder 80)
    - Transkei
      - misc., 1976-1984 (Box 49, Folder 81)
    - Zaire
      - misc., incl. Amnesty International "Reports of torture and killings committed by the armed forces in Shaba region", 1975-1987 (Box 49, Folder 82)
    - Zimbabwe
      - Incl. re. Rhodesian military, 1972-1977 (Box 49, Folder 83)
      - Incl. re. government camps and resettlement, 1975-1977 (Box 49, Folder 84)
      - Negotiations between African nationalists and white minority government, 1975 (Box 49, Folder 85)
      - Incl. re. Zimbabwe African National Union (ZANU), 1976 (Box 49, Folder 86)
      - Incl. re. negotiations, Zimbabwe People's Army (ZIPA), 1976 (Box 49, Folder 87)
      - Incl. re. refugee situation, re. "The Crippled Eagles", Robin Moore, 1976-1979 (Box 49, Folder 88)
      - Anglo-American Proposal, 1977 (Box 49, Folder 89)
      - Paper on Carter Administration policy toward Rhodesia; re. negotiations, 1977 (Box 50, Folder 90)
      - Documents and statements, incl. by Basker Vashee of ZAPU, Takarinda Nyamuswa, Bishop Abel Muzorewa; events time line, etc., 1978 Jan-May (Box 50, Folder 91)
      - Documents and statements, incl. by Abel Muzorewa, Joshua Nkomo; war information; relief agency information, 1978 Jun-Dec (Box 50, Folder 92)
      - Paper by Anthony Wilkinson on impact of war in Zimbabwe; New Year message by Robert Mugabe, other documents and articles, 1979 Jan-Apr (Box 50, Folder 93)
      - Weekly Background Briefings of the Rhodesian Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1979 Apr-Aug (Box 50, Folder 94)
      - Misc. statements and articles, 1979 May-Dec (Box 50, Folder 95)
      - Press releases, report, article re. independence, elections, 1980 (Box 50, Folder 96)
      - Re. U.S. aid to Zimbabwe, 1980 (Box 50, Folder 97)
      - Re. events in Zimbabwe, 1981-1982 (Box 50, Folder 98)
      - Re. U.S. aid to Zimbabwe, 1983-1986 (Box 50, Folder 99)
      - Economy, 1984-1986 (Box 50, Folder 100,101)
      - General, 1980-1989 (Box 50, Folder 102)
      - Military, 1980-1988 (Box 50, Folder 103)
      - Politics, 1985-1987 (Box 50, Folder 104)
      - Religion, 1983-1988 (Box 50, Folder 105)
    - Southern Africa in general
      - Organization of African Unity, 1972-1975 (Box 51, Folder 106)
      - General papers re. situation in Southern Africa, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 107)
      - Southern African Development Coordination Conference, 1980-1987 (Box 51, Folder 108-109)
      - Affect of South Africa on region, 1982-1986 (Box 51, Folder 110)
  - Economic and Foreign Policy issues
    - Arms Trade/ Military Training
      - Arms embargo, 1971-1978 (Box 51, Folder 111,111a)
      - Visit of Admiral James Johnson, 1974 (Box 51, Folder 112)
      - Sale of aircraft to South Africa, 1975-1978 (Box 51, Folder 113-114)
      - Sale of guns to South Africa; Olin-Winchester, Colt, 1976-1979 (Box 51, Folder 115)
      - Space Research Corporation: illegal shipment of arms, 1978-1981 (Box 52, Folder 116-119)
      - Arms trade, 1980-1984 (Box 52, Folder 120-122)
      - Training of S. A. Coast Guard, 1982-1984 (Box 52, Folder 123)
      - Sale of shock batons to S.A., 1982 (Box 52, Folder 124, 124a)
    - Boycotts
      - Academic
        - Medical, 1987 (Box 52, Folder 125)
      - Corporate
        - Oil embargo - general, 1978-1988 (Box 53, Folder 126)
        - Coca Cola, 1986-1989 (Box 53, Folder 127)
        - Coors, 1981-1984 (Box 53, Folder 128)
        - Shell, 1986-1989 (Box 53, Folder 129)
      - Cultural
        - Beverly Hills petition, 1986 (Box 53, Folder 130)
        - misc., 1983-1987 (Box 53, Folder 131)
      - Sports
        - Statements, reports, 1970-1986 (Box 53, Folder 132-133)
    - Divestment / Investment/ Transnational Corporations
      - General (see also Sanctions, and Conferences, below)
        - Reports, statements, incl. "The American Corporation in South Africa: An Analysis" by Timothy H. Smith, 1970-1976 (Box 53, Folder 134)
        - Reports, documents, incl. from Christian Institute of Southern Africa, Beyers Naude, UN Centre Against Apartheid, 1976-1979 (Box 53, Folder 135)
        - Report: "The Disinvestment Movement in the U.S.: a Strategic Analysis"; prepared by The South Africa Foundation, 1980 (Box 53, Folder 136)
        - Report: "The United States and South Africa in the Changing International Division of Labor" by Ann Seidman and Phil O'Keefe; "The Divestment Movement in the U.S.: A Strategic Analysis" prepared by South Africa Foundation, 1980 (Box 53, Folder 137)
        - Report of Symposium on Current Issues Facing American Corporations in South Africa; reports from UN Centre Against Apartheid, 1980-1982 (Box 54, Folder 138)
        - Report: "Transnational Corporations and South Africa's Military Industrial Buildup", ca. 1983 (Box 54, Folder 139)
        - Report: "Black Attitudes, Capitalism and Investment in South Africa"; by Lawrence Schlemmer, 1984 (Box 54, Folder 140)
        - Transcript of The New World Foundation Consultation on Divestment from South Africa, 1985 (Box 54, Folder 141)
        - Report: "Transnational Corporations in South Africa and Namibia"; United National Panel of Eminent Persons, 1985 (Box 54, Folder 142)
        - Re. U.S. bank loans to South Africa, 1980-1986 (Box 54, Folder 143-144)
        - Re. U.S. bank loans to South Africa, 1985-1986 (Box 54, Folder 144)
        - Re. international bank loans to South Africa, 1982-1986 (Box 54, Folder 145)
        - Misc. articles and statements re. corporations' investment in S.A., incl. Canadian and European, 1973-1980 (Box 54, Folder 146)
        - Misc. articles and statements re. corporations' investment in S.A., 1981-1984 (Box 54, Folder 147)
        - Misc. articles and statements re. corporations' investment in S.A., 1985-1987 (Box 54, Folder 148)
        - Information and Resource Kit: "Transnational Corporations in South Africa and Namibia: Aid or Hindrance to Apartheid", compiled by United Nations Non-Governmental Liaison Service, 1985 (Box 54, Folder 149)
      - Re. specific corporations, organizations
        - Anglo-American Corporation of S. Africa (Harry Oppenheimer), 1978-1986 (Box 54, Folder 150)
        - Bank of America; Citibank; Control Data Corp., 1982-1986 (Box 55, Folder 151)
        - Episcopal Church - Committee on South Africa Investments / Episcopal Society for Cultural and Racial Unity, 1969-1970 (Box 55, Folder 152)
        - Ford Motor Company, 1987 (Box 55, Folder 153)
        - General Motors Company; IBM, 1978, 1990 (Box 55, Folder 154)
        - Mobil Corporation; Phelps-Dodge, 1989 (Box 55, Folder 155)
        - Texaco; TIAA-CREF, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 156)
      - State and local campaigns
        - California, 1987, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 157)
        - District of Columbia, 1980-1984 (Box 55, Folder 158-160)
        - Georgia, 1985 (Box 55, Folder 161)
        - Massachusetts, 1978-1981 (Box 55, Folder 162)
        - Washington (Seattle), 1988 (Box 55, Folder 163)
        - Misc., general, 1977-1987, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 164)
      - Sullivan Principles
        - Statements, reports re. Sullivan Principles, a set of equal rights practices for American companies in South Africa, 1977-1978 (Box 55, Folder 165)
        - Statements, reports, 1979-1980 (Box 55, Folder 166)
        - Report by Elizabeth Schmidt: "The Sullivan Principles: Decoding Corporate Camouflage", 1980 (Box 56, Folder 167)
        - Statements, reports, incl. "The Sullivan Principles at Ford - Audit 2", 1981 (Box 56, Folder 168)
        - Statements, reports, incl. "Sixth Report on the Signatory Companies to the Sullivan Principles", 1982 (Box 56, Folder 169)
        - Statements, reports, incl. "Meeting the Mandate of Change: a Progress Report on the Application of the Sullivan Principles by U. S. Companies in South Africa", 1983-1985 (Box 56, Folder 170)
        - Statements, reports, incl. "One Step in the Wrong Direction: An Analysis of the Sullivan Principles as a Strategy for Opposing Apartheid", by Elizabeth Schmidt, and 1987 statement of Leon Sullivan calling for withdrawal of all U.S. companies from S.A., 1985-1987, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 171)
    - Espionage
      - Incl. re. BOSS, Commodore Dieter Gerhardt case, 1983-1987 (Box 56, Folder 172)
      - VAX computer case, ca. 1983 (Box 56, Folder 173)
    - International economics
      - Thesis: "ECOWAS, the Lome Convention, and the New International Economic Order" by Idris M. Abdul-Ghani, 1980 (Box 56, Folder 174)
      - Krugerrands, 1984-1985 (Box 56, Folder 175)
      - International Monetary Fund (see also Series IV - Lobbying Activities/ Monitoring of Legislation), 1980-1985 (Box 56, Folder 176)
    - Trade issues
      - Export-Import
        - Statistics re. Export-Import Bank transactions with S.A. (see also Series IV - Lobbying Activities / Monitoring of Legislation), 1971-1978 (Box 56, Folder 177)
        - Computer printouts re. Export-Import Bank transactions with S.A., 1972-1977 (Box 56, Folder 178)
        - Corres. with unions re. Export-Import Bank, 1978 (Box 56, Folder 179)
        - Export/import of minerals, uranium, gold, 1974-1977, 1989 (Box 56, Folder 180)
        - Misc. clippings and statistics re. exports/imports, 1974-1976 (Box 56, Folder 181)
        - Notes re. export/import activities, 1977-1979 (Box 56, Folder 182)
        - Report: "Export-Import Controls: Their Nature and Accountability" prepared by Church World Service, 1980 (Box 56, Folder 183)
        - Paper: "The African Resource-Exporting States: An Examination of the Frustration of the ...World Periphery" by R. I. Onwuka (10th ICUS conference, Seoul), 1981 (Box 57, Folder 184)
        - Misc. corres., reports re export controls, 1981-1982 (Box 57, Folder 185)
        - Report concerning legal proceedings before the Department of Commerce re. export-import restrictions, 1983 (Box 57, Folder 186)
        - Strategic minerals, and misc. clippings and statistics, 1987-1988 (Box 57, Folder 187)
        - Re. sale of Boeing aircraft to South African Airways, 1989 (Box 57, Folder 188)
        - Memo on "United States Restrictions on Exports to South Africa -- A Reevaluation", 1979 (Box 66, Folder 8)
      - Sanctions
        - Misc. statements re. sanctions, 1973-1987 (Box 57, Folder 189)
        - Views of South African Blacks on sanctions, divestment, 1986-1989,n.d. (Box 57, Folder 190)
        - Misc. statements, reports; "South Africa Sanctions Fact Sheet: Lessons from Rhodesia", by Elizabeth Schmidt, 1986-1988 (Box 57, Folder 191)
        - Report: "The Economic Impact of Sanctions Against South Africa", Starnberger Institut, 1987 (Box 57, Folder 192)
        - Report: "Independent Expert Study on the Evaluation of the Application and Impact of Sanctions - Final Report to the Commonwealth Committee of Foreign Ministers on Southern Africa", 1989 (Box 57, Folder 193)
        - Re. Chris-Mor video against sanctions, 1988 (Box 57, Folder 194)
        - WOA publicity against sanctions, 1988-1989 (Box 57, Folder 195)
        - Misc. labor union related material (Box 57, Folder 196-198)
        - Memo on "Duty of Directors with Respect to Potential Violations of U.S. Law by Foreign Subsidiaries", 1979 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - General / Miscellaneous
    - African-Americans
      - Clippings, articles re. African-Americans and politics in America, 1979-1989 (Box 58, Folder 199)
      - Documentation of various meetings, events, 1981-1983 (Box 58, Folder 200)
      - Martin Luther King, Jr. tributes, events, 1982-1986 (Box 58, Folder 201)
      - Lists of African-American organizations, 1983, 1988 (Box 58, Folder 202)
    - Apartheid - general
      - Definitions, articles re. apartheid, 1977-1986 (Box 58, Folder 203)
      - Christian Century issue on South Africa - theological response to apartheid, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 204)
      - List of Anti-Apartheid groups worldwide, 1979 (Box 58, Folder 205)
      - National Anti-Apartheid Protest Day; Anti-Apartheid Conference, 1985 (Box 58, Folder 206)
      - Films, videos re. apartheid, 1985-1986 (Box 58, Folder 207)
    - Conferences
      - International Youth and Student Movement for the United Nations conferences re. Africa, 1974-1977 (Box 58, Folder 208)
      - United Nations seminar on South Africa, Paris, 1975 (Box 58, Folder 209)
      - Maputo Conference on Zimbabwe and Namibia, 1977 (Box 58, Folder 210)
      - United Nations Seminar on the Role of Transnational Corporations in South Africa and Namibia, Detroit, 1981 (Box 58, Folder 211)
      - Conference in Solidarity with the Liberation Struggles of the Peoples of Southern Africa, Riverside Church, NY, 1981 (Box 58, Folder 212)
      - Conference in Solidarity with the Liberation Struggles of the Peoples of Southern Africa, Riverside Church, NY, 1981-1982 (Box 59, Folder 213)
      - All-Africa Parliamentary Conference on Population and Development, Harare, 1986 (Box 59, Folder 214)
      - Interreligious Consultation on South Africa, Riverside Church, NY, 1986 (Box 59, Folder 215)
    - Education/ Scholarship programs
      - Programs for black South Africans, 1979-1981 (Box 59, Folder 216)
      - Programs for black South Africans, 1982-1983 (Box 59, Folder 217)
    - Files on Individuals (See Series IV for U.S. Legislators)
      - Steven Biko (Box 59, Folder 218)
      - Francois Bill (Box 59, Folder 219)
      - Allan Boesak (Box 59, Folder 220)
      - Julian Bond (Box 59, Folder 221)
      - Breyten Breytenbach (Box 59, Folder 222)
      - Dennis Brutus (Box 59, Folder 223)
      - Dennis Brutus (Box 59, Folder 224)
      - Chief Mangosuthu G. Buthelezi (Box 59, Folder 225)
      - Willis Carto (Box 59, Folder 226)
      - Frank Chikane (Box 59, Folder 227)
      - Nathaniel Davis (Box 60, Folder 228)
      - Dean Simon Farisani (Box 60, Folder 229)
      - Alexander Haig (Box 60, Folder 230)
      - Archbishop Hurley (Box 60, Folder 231)
      - Duke Kent-Brown (Box 60, Folder 232)
      - William Keyes (Box 60, Folder 233)
      - Coretta Scott King (Box 60, Folder 234)
      - Henry Kissinger (Box 60, Folder 235)
      - Lyndon Larouche (Box 60, Folder 236)
      - Ernest Lefever (Box 60, Folder 237)
      - Ernest Lefever (Box 60, Folder 238)
      - Tseitsi Mahanini (Box 60, Folder 239)
      - Smangoliso Mkhatshwa (Box 60, Folder 240)
      - Bishop Abel Muzorewa (Box 60, Folder 241)
      - Herman Nickel (Box 60, Folder 242)
      - Buert SerVaas (Box 60, Folder 243)
      - Maurice Smithers (Box 61, Folder 244)
      - Richard John Stevens (Box 61, Folder 245)
      - Leon Sullivan (See also: Sanctions, above) (Box 61, Folder 246)
      - Florence Tate (Box 61, Folder 247)
      - Desmond Tutu (Box 61, Folder 248)
      - Desmond Tutu (Box 61, Folder 249)
      - Desmond Tutu (Box 61, Folder 250)
      - David Webster (Box 61, Folder 251)
      - Andrew Young (Box 61, Folder 252)
    - Media